Guide to the Thomas F. Garbett papers, 1908-1992 and undated RL.00431
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Thomas F. Garbett papers
1908-1992 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Garbett, Thomas F.
RL.00431
896
7.6 Linear Feet
3450 Items
Author and advertising executive with the Doyle Dane Bernbach agency and Brouillard Communications, a division of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), based in New York. Collection consists mainly of research files on various topics in corporate advertising and those prepared for Garbett's book, Corporate Advertising: the What, the Why, and the How (1981). Also contains miscellaneous files reflecting his work at Brouillard Communications, including advertisements for Textron, inc., and Eaton Corporation, as well as unsorted examples of corporate advertising taken from U.S. magazines and newspapers. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Thomas F. Garbett papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
Advertising executive and author whose career included work at the Doyle Dane Bernbach agency, where he was Senior Vice President, and Brouillard Communications, Inc. (a division of the J. Walter Thompson Company).
Collection Overview
Collection consists mainly of research files on various topics in corporate advertising and those prepared for Garbett's book, Corporate Advertising: the What, the Why, and the How (1981). Also contains miscellaneous files reflecting his work at Brouillard Communications, including advertisements for Textron, inc., and Eaton Corporation, as well as unsorted examples of corporate advertising taken from U.S. magazines and newspapers. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General and Subject Files; Print Advertising and Photographs; Publications of the Association of National Advertisers (ANA); and Writings
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications vertical files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation vertical files
Douglass L. Alligood papers
John R. Blaney papers
Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising -- History; Institutional advertising; Eaton Corporation; Brouillard Communications, Inc.; Garbett, Thomas F. Corporate advertising; J. Walter Thompson Company; Garbett, Thomas F.; Textron, Inc.; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General and Subject Files, 1957-1992 and undated; 1
  - 3M Corporate Advertising (Karl Kaufman and Bruce Sutherland), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Acquisition, 1978-1988; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Advertising Age--William Bernbach: He was never a slave to the rules, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Advertising effectiveness, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Advertising effectiveness--W.R. Grace case study, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Advocacy, 1977-1987; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Assessing the Long-Term Value of Advertising (Nariman Dhalla), 1978 (Box 1)
  - Brouillard--The Winning Edge: Study of corporate reputations (Box 1)
  - Business Week--Corporate Advertising Portfolio, 1986 (Box 14)
  - CEO as spokesperson, 1978-1988; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Conference Board--Annual Survey of Corporate Contributions, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Conference Board--Managing Corporate External Relations, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Copy testing, 1973-1993; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Corporate Advertising and the Prospective Employee (Karen Smith, MA thesis), 1988 (Box 2)
  - Corporate communications, 1969-1984 (Box 2)
  - Corporate communications planning, undated (Box 17)
  - Corporate giving/Social responsibility, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Corporate identity, 1982-1986 (Box 3)
  - Corporate image, 1971-1992 (Box 3)
  - Corporate leadership, 1982-1987 (Box 3)
  - Corporate logo quiz, undated (Box 3)
  - Corporate name change, 1965-1988; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Council for Advancement and Support of Education (CASE)--Matching gifts, etc., 1983-1987 (Box 3)
  - Creative, 1958-1990; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Creativity and the Corporate Brand (Jim Johnston), 1989 (Box 4)
  - DDB (Doyle Dane Bernbach)--Focus on Effect (Ruth Ziff), undated (Box 4)
  - DDB Needham--Lifestyle studies, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - DDB Needham--Understanding Brand Loyalty, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Dimensions of Advertising Research (Steve Marchant), 1983 (Box 4)
  - Diversified company data, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Does Corporate Image Advertising Work? (Donald Frenette), 1989 (Box 4)
  - Doremus--Tombstone advertising (financial services/Securities advertisements), undated (Box 4)
  - Eaton Corporation, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Evaluating the Corporate Image Campaign (Robert Worcester), 1981 (Box 4)
  - Financial Times--Corporate Advertising: Menace, Myth or Magic Formula?, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Government influence on advertising, 1957-1979 (Box 4)
  - GTE corporate image program, undated (Box 4)
  - Investment Community Attitudes toward Companies with Multi-Industry Exposure, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Investor relations, 1981-1986 (Box 5)
  - Issue advocacy/advertising, 1978-1986 (Box 5)
  - Marketing Revolution (Kevin Clancy, Robert Shulman), 1992 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1991; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Mission statements, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Multi-Media Service Corporate and Association Reports, 1983-1992 (Box 5)
  - Multi-Media Service Corporate and Association Reports, 1985-1991; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - New York City Partnership (corporate giving), 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Organizing corporate communications, 1971-1984 (Box 6)
  - Organizing for Global Identity (Maureen Hartigan), undated (Box 6)
  - Picking an advertising agency, 1976-1987 (Box 6)
  - Public Relations Journal, 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Suppliers, 1991-1992 (Box 7)
  - Survey research, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Time--Bethlehem case study, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Time--Corporate Image and Trade in Europe in the 1990s, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Time--Corporate Images in Asia, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Time--EuroImages: Perception of the Top Companies in Europe, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Time--Family opinion panel on U.S. corporations, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Time--Measuring the Effectiveness of Strategic Advertising, undated (Box 7)
  - Time--Study of Corporate Advertising Effectiveness, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Time--Strategic Advertising and Attitudes Toward Corporations, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Tracking corporate image, 1971-1986; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Trends, 1985-1991 (Box 8)
  - Washington Post--Crisis Communications Seminar, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Westinghouse case study: "You Can Be Sure" campaign (Robert Lukovics), 1983 (Box 8)
  - What's Really Behind this Year's Double Digit Drip in Corporate Advertising? (Ed McEwen), 1991 (Box 8)
  - Where Is Corporate Advertising Headed?, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Yankelovich Monitor, 1991 (Box 8)
- Print Advertising and Photographs, 1908-1991 and undated; 2
  - Advocacy, 1980s; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Advocacy, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Allied Corporation, 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - AMCA International, undated (Box 14)
  - American Iron and Steel Institute/United Steelworkers of America, 1950 and undated (Box 14)
  - Anaconda, 1950 (Box 14)
  - Bell Telephone/Bell System, 1951-1984 and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Bendix, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Borg-Warner, 1951-1953 (Box 14)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway/Nickel Plate Road, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Chrysler, 1986-1988 (Box 15)
  - CIGNA, 1982 (Box 15)
  - Continental Telephone, 1982 (Box 15)
  - Corning, 1947-1950 (Box 15)
  - Dow Chemical, 1951-1952 (Box 15)
  - Eaton Corporation, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Eaton Corporation, 1972; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Eaton Corporation, 1971-1980 and undated; 6 folders (Box 15)
  - Eaton Corporation, 1972-1980; 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Electric Light and Power Companies, 1950-1951 (Box 16)
  - General Motors, 1948-1953 (Box 16)
  - GTE/Sylvania, undated (Box 16)
  - Kuppers Chemicals, 1956-1959 (Box 16)
  - McGraw-Hill, undated (Box 16)
  - Mergers and acquisitions, 1984-1989 (Box 17)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance, 1950s-1966 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous corporate ads, 1908-1991; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous corporate ads, 1947-1989; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Name change, 1981-1988 and undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Name change, 1983-1989 (Box 16)
  - Name change, 1986-1991; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Picking an advertising agency (Johnston Thoen & Lindh), undated (Box 16)
  - Republic Steel, undated (Box 16)
  - Stroh's beer, undated (Box 16)
  - Textron, 1974-1976 (Box 16)
  - Ticor Title Insurance, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Trane, 1950-1951 (Box 16)
  - Transco Energy, 1982 (Box 16)
  - "Tune-In" (sponsored broadcast), 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Union Pacific, 1982 (Box 16)
  - United Aircraft, 1950-1952 (Box 16)
  - United States Steel, 1947-1959 (Box 16)
  - Unusual ads, 1984-1989 (Box 9)
  - Unusual ads, 1984-1990 (Box 17)
  - Western Electric, 1946-1963 (Box 16)
  - World War II-era, 1941-1945 (Box 9)
  - Proof sheet, 1983 (Box 9)
- Publications of the Association of National Advertisers (ANA), 1975-1991; 3
  - Address by William Simon, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Advertising and Human Nature (Donald Kanter), 1983 (Box 10)
  - Are Some Corporations More Equal Than Others? (Herbert Schmertz, Mobil), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Can the Effectiveness of Corporate Advertising Be Measured Accurately? (John Lowden, ITT), 1975 (Box 10)
  - Corporation's Responsibility to Communicate (Roger Smith, GM), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Advertising: Is It Worth the Money? (Larry Light, BBDO), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Advertising: Making It Work in a Shifting Environment (Karl Koss, GE), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Advertising Practices, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Communications: Which Alternatives? (John Howland, AT&T), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Communications Conference: Ed McEwen speech, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Current Trends in the Way Companies Are Using Corporate Advertising, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Difference is the Difference (Raymond D'Argenio), 1980 (Box 10)
  - Effect of Brand Advertising on Company Image (Lewis Winters, Standard Oil), 1983 (Box 10)
  - Growing Tomorrow's Markets with Corporate Advertising (Charles Francis, IBM), 1982 (Box 10)
  - How DuPont Uses Television for Corporate Advertising (Raymond Alfano), 1980 (Box 10)
  - How Stockholders Profit from Corporate Advertising (Jaye Niefeld, Bozell & Jacobs), 1978 (Box 10)
  - How to Improve the Return on Investment of Your Corporate Advertising, 1980 (Box 10)
  - How corporate communications will differ in the 80s vs. the 70s (Murray Hillman, Interpublic), 1980 (Box 10)
  - Identifying an Industry's Issues Among Key Audiences (Rene Zentner, Shell Oil), 1980 (Box 10)
  - Identifying Corporate Needs (Robert Lundy, TRW), 1975 (Box 10)
  - New Media (Lee Pratt, Brouillard), 1980 (Box 10)
  - Pace of Television (Herbert Krugman), 1983 (Box 10)
  - People's Expectations (Gene Pokorny), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Performance Story (Paul Cleek and Richard Peters, Phillips Petroleum), 1980 (Box 10)
  - Predictable Future (John Naisbitt), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Progress Is Our Most Important Image (General Electric), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Redefining Communication (Joel Dubow, Coca-Cola), 1983 (Box 10)
  - Selecting an Advertising Agency, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Speaking Frankly and Liking It (John Martin, Aetna), 1979 (Box 10)
  - Strategic Orientation (Robert Williams, DuPont), 1988 (Box 10)
  - Survey on Corporate Advertising Trends, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Targeting Communications to Change Public Attitudes (Gene Pokorny), 1980 (Box 10)
  - The Public: Business's Ally or Adversary? (Eric Weiss, Sun), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Tracking the Effects of Corporate Advertising (Herbert Krugman, GE), 1981 (Box 10)
  - We Can't Wait for Tomorrow (Blair Gettig and Dale Worcester, ALCOA), 1979 (Box 10)
- Writings, 1964-1991; 4
  - Book File (Corporate Advertising), 1964-1994 and undated; 1
    - Objectives, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Introduction, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Chapter 2: Corporate advertising vs. issue advertising, 1975-1982; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Chapter 3: Size and scope, 1977-1979; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Chapter 4: The basic pros and cons, 1975-1980 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 5: Corporate advertising's relationship to product advertising, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 6: Corporate advertising to the financial community, 1971-1980; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Chapter 7: Corporate advertising and employees, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 8: Corporate advertising and acquisitions, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Chapter 9: Advertising in a recession, 1981-1990; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Chapter 10: Applying market disciplines to corporate advertising, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Chapter 12-13, 1978-1987; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Chapter 13: Appropriate audience, 1975-1979 (Box 12)
    - Chapter 14: Budgets, 1964-1977 (Box 12)
    - Chapter 15: Creative process, 1971-1980 (Box 12)
    - Chapter 17: Media considerations, 1975-1979 (Box 12)
    - Book 3 (revise of Book 1), 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - Book 3 (revise of Book 1), 1970-1986; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Clippings, 1976-1991 (Box 16)
    - Clippings, 1977-1994; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 16)
  - Other Writings by Garbett, 1982-1991; 2
    - Ads in a Recession, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Corporate Ads and Corporate Image (interview by Rod Willis), 1991 (Box 13)
    - Corporate Advertising from Image to Advocacy, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Kaleidescope: Overview of 80s corporate advertising, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Researching Corporate Advertising, 1983 (Box 13)
    - What Happens When Corporate Ad Budgets Are Cut?, 1983 (Box 13)
    - What Happens When You Cut Corporate Advertising, 1985 (Box 13)